censured for showing cowardice in the battle.
Once again, some of the animals heard this with a certain bewilderment, but
Squealer was soon able to convince them that their memories had been at fault.
In the autumn, by a tremendous exhausting effort, for the harvest had to be gathered at
almost the same time, the windmill was finished.
The machinery had still to be installed, and Whymper was negotiating the purchase of it,
but the structure was completed.
In the teeth of every difficulty, in spite of inexperience, of primitive
implements, of bad luck, and of Snowball's treachery, the work had been finished punctually to
the very day.
Tired out, but proud, the animals walked round and round their masterpiece, which
appeared even more beautiful in their eyes than when it had been built the first time.
Moreover, the walls were twice as thick as before.
Nothing short of explosives would lay them low this time.
And when they thought of how they had labored, what discouragements they had
overcome, and the enormous difference that would be made in their lives when
the sails were turning and the dynamos running, when they thought of all this,
their tiredness forsook them, and they gamboled round and round the
windmill, uttering cries of triumph.
Napoleon himself, attended by his dogs and his cockerel, came down to inspect
the completed work.
He personally congratulated the animals on their achievement,
and announced that the mill would be named Napoleon Mill.
Two days later, the animals were called together for a special meeting in the barn.
They were struck dumb with surprise when Napoleon announced that he had sold the
pile of timber to Frederick.
Tomorrow, Frederick's wagons would arrive and begin carting it away.
Throughout the whole period of his seeming friendship with Pilkington,
Napoleon had really been in secret agreement with Frederick.
All relations with Foxwood had been broken off.
Insulting messages had been sent to Pilkington.
The pigeons had been told to avoid Pinchfield Farm and to alter their
slogan from death to Frederick to death to Pilkington.
At the same time, Napoleon assured the animals that the stories of an impending
attack on Animal Farm were completely untrue, and that the tales about Frederick's
cruelty to his own animals had been greatly exaggerated.
All these rumors had probably originated with Snowball and his agents.
It now appeared that Snowball was not, after all, hiding on Pinchfield Farm,
and, in fact, had never been there in his life.
He was living in considerable luxury, so it was said, that Foxwood,
and had, in reality, been a pensioner of Pilkington for years past.
The pigs were in ecstasies over Napoleon's cunning.
By seeming to be friendly with Pilkington, he had forced Frederick to raise his price by 12 lb.
But the superior quality of Napoleon's mind, said Squealer, was shown in the
fact that he trusted nobody, not even Frederick.
Frederick had wanted to pay for the timber with something called a check,
which, it seemed, was a piece of paper with a promise to pay written upon it.
But Napoleon was too clever for him.
He had demanded payment in real 5 lb notes, which were to be handed over
before the timber was removed.
Already, Frederick had paid up, and the sum he had paid was just enough to buy
the machinery for the windmill.
Meanwhile, the timber was being carted away at high speed.
When it was all gone, another special meeting was held in the barn for the
animals to inspect Frederick's banknotes.
Smiling beatifically, and wearing both his decorations, Napoleon reposed on a
bed of straw on the platform, with the money at his side, neatly piled on a
China dish from the farmhouse kitchen.